<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<statements>
	<statement id="1">Low income hinders people from engaging in sustainable initiatives.</statement>
	<statement id="2">Meeting basic daily needs is more important than being eco-friendly.</statement>
	<statement id="3">Sustainable neighborhoods lead to gentrification which excludes people with low socio-economic status.</statement>
	<statement id="4">Socioeconomic differences lead to an imbalance in participation in sustainability.</statement>
	<statement id="5">Sustainability efforts will be insufficient until economic imbalances are eliminated.</statement>
	<statement id="6">The success of sustainable practices is dependent on the participation of all stakeholders.</statement>
	<statement id="7">Partnerships among social groups from different neighborhoods will close the gap between how much the residents of each neighborhood engage in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="8">Participation in community activities leads to active and responsible citizens who are more likely to respond to environmental challenges.</statement>
	<statement id="9">Getting the entire community on board with sustainability is essential for behavioural change to occur.</statement>
	<statement id="10">Community-based organizations should facilitate social support networks and provide the space necessary to hold meetings and share knowledge and resources on sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="11">There are not enough information and resources accessible to people with a low socio-economic status to be well-informed about sustainable practices.</statement>
	<statement id="12">Gaining relevant knowledge and skills lead to an individual’s empowerment to act as an environmentally responsible citizen.</statement>
	<statement id="13">Positive personal experiences in nature, outdoor education programs, and environmental role models foster environmental sensitivity in an individual.</statement>
	<statement id="14">Awareness alone doesn't lead to engagement in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="15">A low literacy rate and lack of language proficiency are barriers to engagement in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="16">If municipalities want low-income communities to engage more in sustainability issues, then they should host neighbourhood leadership workshops to help them improve their leadership skills and understand democratic processes.</statement>
	<statement id="17">We need to strengthen climate change education to increase engagement in climate change action.</statement>
	<statement id="18">Peer pressure fosters engagement in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="19">Monetary incentives that reward sustainable behaviour are great tools to get citizens engaged in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="20">Visible change towards sustainability in neighborhoods (like the creation of green spaces) will encourage its residents to act more sustainably themselves.</statement>
	<statement id="21">A city must have infrastructure that facilitates its residents' engagement in environmental issues, for example, by enabling them to report their neighborhoods' needs.</statement>
	<statement id="22">The low engagement of low socio-economic status residents in sustainability issues can be attributed to sustainability being a predominantely white movement in which BIPOC (Black, Indigenous and People of Color) are underrepresented.</statement>
	<statement id="23">Increased equality between neighbourhoods would positively influence environmental features, like less toxicity and less pollution.</statement>
	<statement id="24">An improved infrastructure network of public transport would be an opportunity to the engagement of low socio-economic status residents because people would be more mobile, and thus more able to engage.</statement>
	<statement id="25">Sustainable behavior is not as easily achievable for BIPOC (Black, Indigenous and People of Color) and people with low socio-economic status, thus racial and social equality must be a priority in all sustainabilty efforts.</statement>
	<statement id="26">Neighboorhood networks for sharing goods and knowledge of repair are essential for residents' engagement in sustainability issues.</statement>
	<statement id="27">Changing behaviour at a large scale is difficult, especially when the behaviours to be changed are reinforced and maintained by our physical and social environments.</statement>
	<statement id="28">Engagement in sustainability issues is hindered by our economic system that is designed to get the most, the best, the newest, and the fastest.</statement>
	<statement id="29">Resident-driven efforts to address environmental issues are a great way to change the behavior of locals.</statement>
	<statement id="30">Wijkambassadors are an important group to involve in environmental issues since they can influence a neighborhood's sustainability efforts in the long-run.</statement>
	<statement id="31">The perception of sustainability as an upper-class movement hinders people with low socio-economic status from participating.</statement>
	<statement id="32">People with a low socio-economic status would engage more in sustainability if they were given a say over how the sustainable transition happens.</statement>
	<statement id="33">Trained volunteers should reach out to locals (through paper flyers in mailboxes, door-to-door canvassing, and online social media groups) to give them the opportunity to voice their environmental concerns.</statement>
	<statement id="34">A big challenge with engaging people with low socio-economic status through community participation initiatives is that they are disheartened and disappointed and thus don’t believe change is possible due to past experiences of exclusion from decision-making.</statement>
	<statement id="35">A community’s capacity for change is reflected in residents’ sense of community or the idea that neighbors have shared expectations, trust, and willingness to take action together.</statement>
	<statement id="36">Poor households should not be judged for their low engagement in sustainability issues since their lifestyle has the least impact on the environment.</statement>
	<statement id="37">People with low socio-economic status are indifferent to sustainability issues. Therefore, efforts to get them engaged are redundant.</statement>
	<statement id="38">People with low income have the lowest impact on the environment. To go green, target the middle and upper class, not the lower class.</statement>
	<statement id="39">All residents have equal responsibility to engage in sustainability issues, regardless of socio-economic status.</statement>
	<statement id="40">The perception of sustainability to be an elitist movement is unjustified, because many practices, such as reusing, buying second-hand, and using public transport, have been the habits of working class people for years.</statement>
</statements>
